CURRICULUM VITAE

JACKSON JESSEL ABOAGYE – AGBI (MPhil)

(Mathematics Teacher Educator)

Mailing Address

Accra College of Education
Department of Mathematics and ICT
P. O. Box LG 221
Legon-Accra

Contact Information

Tel: +233 548355164/ +233 502028998 Email: jacksonaboagye86@gmail.com or jackwebenterprise@gmail.com

Website: http://www.jackwebenterp.com

WhatsApp & Telegram:+233 548355164

Residential Address: Ashaiman Lebanon Zone 5, near Tema C22

CAREER FOCUS AND PHILOSOPHY

The 21st century; an entrepreneurial and technology-driven era requires mathematics teachers with comprehensive and durable knowledge to teach with understanding in their academic disciplines to influence student learning. As a result, my career emphasis is to train mathematics teachers to develop and be intellectually capable and curious, so that they will position themselves to respond to the diversity of human conditions and problems that impact our educational processes.

It has also been my desire to train mathematics teachers to fit themselves in relevant and purposeful ways in their exposure with others in their educational pursuits. In building positively strong correlation between teacher professionalism and societal change, I desired to train mathematics teachers to become aware of the realism of human relations and how individuals or groups of different background interact within and between groups.

I am a dedicated, self-motivated, innovative, entrepreneurial and hardworking Ghanaian with stronger interested in areas that require mathematical and technological needs as well as developing materials and resources to promote mathematical and technological concepts. I have extensive experience in manipulating data analysis software, designing of websites and database, and also intermediate knowledge on computer hardware and networking.

As dreamed of becoming a mentor, I value academic excellence and integrity, outstanding teaching and service, effective professional leadership, individual and collective excellence, multiplicity, fairness and social justice, lifelong education of individuals, and collaboration.

I hereby strongly believe that with my integrity, intelligence, and energy I can contribute to the achievement of any organisational goal.

ACADEMIC DEGREES

M.Phil. Mathematics (Edu.) University of Education, Winneba, Ghana. Aug. 2016 to 2019 Research (Thesis): *The Nature and Causes of Mathematical Anxiety among*

Senior High School Students.

B.Sc. Mathematics (Edu.) University of Education, Winneba, Ghana. Aug. 2011 to Jul. 2015

Research Work: Addressing Students Difficulties in Solving Three Set Problems with Venn diagram using Practical Approach in Presbyterian Boys Senior High

School, Legon, Accra.

Diploma Basic Education, Dambai College of Education, Dambai, Ghana, Sept. 2004 to Aug. 2007

CONFERENCE(S)/ SEMINAR(S)/ SUMIT(S)/ WORKSHOP(S) ATTENDED

June 1st to 2nd, 2017 : Africa Research and Innovation Summit, (Association of African Universities)

April 24th to 25th, 2018: Maiden Thesis and Proposal Writing Seminar, (GRASAG-UEW, IERIS & SGS)

February 16th, 2021 : Right to Play Workshop, (Accra College of Education)

WORK EXPERIENCE

2021 to date : Tutor, Accra College of Education, Department of Mathematics and ICT

Courses: *Teaching, learning and applying Further Algebra, STS*

2019 to date : Lecturer, Institute of Distance and e-Learning, University of Education,

Winneba. (Part-Time)

Courses: Mathematics Curriculum, Algebra II, Numerical Analysis, Introductory Analysis, Partial Differential Equation (PDE), Trigonometry, Linear Algebra, Web Technology, Mathematics Methodology, Teaching Learning and Applying Number and Algebra, and Mathematics in Early Years.

Number of Research work supervised: 7

Number of Research work under supervision: 17

2016 – 2018 : Headmaster Academic & Subject teacher, Fairview Educational Centre, Jukwa

2015 – 2016 : Content Developer, Catalyst Learning Limited, Winneba

Developing teachers guide, students notebook, workbook, and assessment

materials for basics schools in Mathematics.

2008 – 2011 : Subject Teacher (Mathematics and ICT), GES, Borae No.2 D/A Junior High

School (Borae, Krachi West District, Volta Region). Circuit Sports and Culture

Organizer, GES Borae Circuit.

2007 – 2008 : Class Teacher (Basic 6), GES, Borae No.2 D/A Primary "A" School (Borae,

Krachi West District, Volta Region)

INTENSHIPS

2014 : Teacher Interns, Presbyterian Boy's Senior High School, Legon, Ghana

2006 – 2007 : Attachment, Osramanae D/A JHS, Osramanae, Krachi West, Ghana.

COMMITTEES

2017 – 2018 : GRASAG-UEW EC committee (Deputy Electoral Commissioner)
 2016 – 2017 : GRASAG-UEW EC committee (University of Education, Winneba)
 2014 – 2015 : AMES-ICT committee (Adviser, University of Education, Winneba)

OFFICES HELD

2016 – 2018	 O Course Rep. M.Phil. Mathematics Education, 2016/2017 academic year group. O Senator GRASAG-UEW O GRASAG-UEW EC Deputy Electoral Commissioner
2013 – 2014 (At University of Education, Winneba)	 O President, DATCOSA UEW Branch O President, ICT Club AMES-UEW O Special Consultant to the AMES ICT Committee UEW.
2012 – 2013 (At University of Education, Winneba)	 Organizing Secretary, DATCOSA UEW Branch Organizing Secretary, Master Seed (NUPS – G, UEW)
2008 – 2011 (Borae No.2 Junior High School)	O Staff SecretaryO HIV/ AIDS Club President
2005 – 2006 (At Dambai College of Education)	 O Compound Overseer, Ayesu Hall O Drum Major, College Choir O President, NUPS – G O Vice President, Environmental Youth Club (Dambai College of Education, Dambai)

NATIONAL DUTIES

2020	National Trainer (Comprehensive Food Security and Vulnerability Assessment
	Survey [CFSVA]), (GSS, MOFA, WFP & FAO)
2010	National Population and Housing Census (Enumerator Krachi West district)
2008	Polling Assistant (Borae Electoral Area)

ADDITIONAL SKILLS

- O Confident with the use of IT and statistical packages such as Ms Word, PowerPoint, Microsoft Excel, Publisher and SPSS. I have used these packages both at work and in school.
- O Website designing, developing and managing of web applications and MySQL database.
 - Website and web application designing languages ever worked with: Html, Html5, CSS, CSS3, JavaScript, JQuery and Bootstrap.
 - o Server-side languages ever worked with: JQuery, Ajax, and Php.
 - o Database languages ever worked with: MySQL database.
 - o Desktop application languages ever worked with: Java and VB.net.

INTERESTS

Choral activities, coding and browsing, and Football games.

LANGUAGES SPOKEN

English, Ewe, and Twi

Number of Dependants: 5

REFEREES

Prof. Damian Kofi Mereku
Senior Lecturer, Dept. of Mathematics Edu.
University of Education, Winneba
P. O. Box 25, Winneba, Ghana
Email: kofi.mereku@yahoo.com

+233 24 496 1318

Jones D. Apawu (Ph. D)
Senior Lecturer, Dept. of Mathematics Edu.
Faculty of Science Education

Department of Mathematics Education Coordinator of ETI @ EFPO

Mathematics Coordinator IDeL
University of Education, Winneba

P. O. Box 25, Winneba

Email: jonesapawu2010@gmail.com +233 24 448 7323/ +233 208055672 Dr. Gloria Armah (Mrs.)

Senior Lecturer, Dept. of Mathematics Edu. Department of Mathematics Education University of Education, Winneba P. O. Box 25, Winneba

+233 201043128

Prof. Micheal Johnson Nabie

Senior Lecturer, Dept. of Mathematics Edu. Head of Department: Mathematics Edu. University of Education, Winneba

P. O. Box 25, Winneba, Ghana

Email: <u>nabizie@yahoo.com</u> Tel.: +233(0) 20 654 5697